

email: <u>will.k.01@live.co.uk</u>

> portfolio: wknight.dev

phone: 07807 904232

github: williamxb

About me

I'm a Web Developer with nearly 5 years in the Technology industry, and 2 years of professionally creating websites. I work primarily in WordPress, building bespoke themes from scratch with modern HTML, CSS, and JS/jQuery. I also have some experience with Git workflows, React (Gatsby) and Python.

Skills

CSS • HTML • PHP • JavaScript • jQuery • **React • WordPress** • GraphQL • SEO • Linux/CLI • **Tailwind CSS** • Bootstrap 4/5 • Ecommerce

Github/Git • Docker & Compose • VS Code • Jamstack • Virtualisation (VMWare ESXi)

Experience

Junior Web Developer • Blue Smarty

Sept. 2019 - July 2021

Creating websites from scratch to exceed our client's expectations.

Responsibilities and achievements include:

- Communication with the client
- Technology choices (CSS Frameworks, IDEs, technical direction on new builds)
- Design and implementation of website builds
- Identifying bugs and implementing fixes
- Implementation of tweaks and new features
- Optimise websites using PageSpeed, Lighthouse, GTmetrix, Core Web Vitals
- Tooling optimization

Technologies used: WordPress, CSS, HTML, PHP, jQuery, JavaScript

Junior SEO Developer • Search Intelligence

Mar. 2018 - Sept. 2019

I utilised various strategies to build relevant and engaging content which links to ours and our client's websites. In addition to SEO, I contributed to the development of multiple internal and client websites, allowing me to develop a foundation of knowledge and skill with front-end development of WordPress using page builder plugins alongside some basic HTML and CSS.

Technical Assistant • Cloudworxs

Oct. 2016 - Nov. 2017

My tasks and responsibilities included populating the various online stores including Amazon and eBay, alongside computer hardware projects including refurbishment and repairs. I also assisted with pick and pack order fulfilment for products stored on-site.

Personal Projects

DVLA Discord Bot

Discord chat-bot in Python which takes a UK vehicle registration, and returns basic details about the vehicle from the DVLA VES API

Technologies used: Python, discord.py, HTTP REST API, JSON

My Homelab • Private

Technologies used: VMware ESXi, Linux, Docker, Docker Compose, OpenVPN

My Website • wknight.dev • Github

Technologies used: React, Gatsby, TailwindCSS, GraphQL, Netlify

Education

Computer Science • BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma

Grade achieved: Distinction*, Distinction, Distinction/D*DD

A Level Equivalent: A*AA

Throughout the course I developed a wide variety of soft skills including time and project management, communication and teamwork skills, while significantly broadening my knowledge of the computing industry.